Guide to the George Washington University COVID-19 collection, 2020-2021 RG0155
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University COVID-19 collection
2020-2021
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0155
100 item(s) Contains video oral histories, images and other digital files. All digital.
This collection documents the experiences of the students, staff, faculty and community during the COVID-19 pandemic.
Arrangement
Collection will be organized into series. There will be series for the web archives and social media; the student survey conducted by the University Archvies; and the material collected and donated by faculty.
Biographical / Historical
On March 13, 2020, the President of the United States declared a national emergency in response to the growing number of COVID-19 cases nationwide. George Washington University pivoted to online learning at that time. This collection is an effort to document and identify for future researchers how the University responded to the virus.
Scope and Contents
The collection was created by the University Archivist and contains material collected by the Archives as well as by faculty.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was partially harvested and archived through Archive-It and Social Feed Manager. The video files were transferred and donated by the person being interviewed.
Conditions Governing Access
Some materials are restricted.
COVID-19 (Disease); Coronavirus infections; George Washington University -- Students; Student activities; Faculty; COVID-19 Pandemic, 2020-
- GWU COVID-19 Web Archives, Harvested from the web starting March 12, 2020.; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  Websites were captured using Archive-it and show the University's response and how it kept the community informed during the pandemic.
  - Campus advisories, 2020 March 12 - 2020 August 7; Series 1
    GW Campus Advisory alerts related to Covid-19. This is the main page of alerts; each individual page was also captured and is available.
    This page was retired and replaced with coronavirus.gwu.edu.
  - Prevention, 2020 March 12 - 2020 August 7; Series 1
    Prevention information at GW in response to Covid-19.
  - Frequently Asked Questions, 2020 March 12 - 2020 July 26; Series 1
    Website for questions related to Covid-19 at the university.
  - Campus response, 2020 March 12 - 2020 July 25; Series 1
    Information on GW's response to Covid-19.
  - Travel Advisories, 2020 March 12 - 2020 July 25; Series 1
    The university suspended all non-essential, GW-affiliated international travel for students, faculty and staff beginning in March to help protect members of our community from the global spread of COVID-19. As we continue to monitor the situation and based on guidance from our public health experts, we have determined that it is necessary to continue the suspension of all non-essential international travel until further notice.
  - University updates, 2020 April 9 - 2020 July 25; Series 1
    Updates put out by the University during Covid-19.
  - GW Coronavirus Response, 2020-2021; Series 1
    Main webpage for GWU's response to Covid-19. This became the site for coronavirus information in place of the Campus Advisories.
- Culture and the Coronavirus: A GW Documentary Project, 2020-2021; Series 2; 47 digital object(s) 47 oral histories as well as photographs and videos.
  All materials in this series are from the documentary project, run by GW American Studies professor Melani McAlister.
  Biographical / Historical
  In collaboration between the GW Library and Melani McAlister, Professor of American Studies and International Affairs, these materials document the experience and responses of the George Washington University community to the COVID crisis, while also providing a showcase for humanities and social science research on the pandemic. The project includes two components: the collection of oral histories and archival materials, and a website of exhibits and scholarship that draws in part on those materials. Culture and the Coronavirus aims to document the social and political impact of the pandemic, including the impact of choices made by government, medical practitioners, individuals, and GW itself.
  The project has assembled personal memories and reflections from a broad swath of the GW community--students, staff, faculty, and alumni. Over the summer of 2020, with a small amount of funding from the American Studies department, Professor McAlister directed a research team of three students who conducted interviews with 35 GW students and faculty. Further plans involve doing more interviews, focusing particularly on staff and alumni, along with collecting and documenting other kinds of materials: photographs, emails, and journal entries.
  The work continued through 2021 and expanded to include other adminstrators and GW-related individuals.
  - Interview: Abera, Lydia, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:39:57
    Accruals
    Oral history is part of volume 1, the first grouping that was transferred to the University Archives.
  - Interview: Al Jariri, Rozan, 2020 June 19; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:31:02
  - Interview: Alizoti, Zubaidah, 2020 June 29; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in Political Science interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:22:32
  - Interview: Azadi, Mona, 2020 June 16; Series 2
    Graduate student and staff member interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:39:25
  - Interview: Balas, Henry, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in American Studies/Political Science interviewed by Sydney Teabout. Length of interview: 0:38:17
  - Interview: Cheuk, Eric, 2020 June 18; Series 2
    Graduate Student in American Studies interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:26:01
  - Interview: Cook, Ian, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in International Affairs interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:36:57
  - Interview: Dolan, Thomas Simsarian, 2020 June 18; Series 2
    Graduate student in American Studies interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:52:45
  - Interview: Donnelly, Erin, 2020 June 24; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in International Affairs interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:55:33
  - Interview: Fraser, Shealyn, 2020 June 30; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in American Studies/SMPA interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:49:02
  - Interview: Guzewich, Ellis, 2020 June 24; Series 2
    Graduate student in SEAS/Mechanical and Aerospace interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:39:36
  - Interview: Hirsch, Trevor, 2020 June 30; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in history interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:38:14
  - Interview: Kamsler, Brigette, 2020 July 7; Series 2
    University Archivist and staff member in Libraries and Academic Innovation interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:28:26
  - Interview: Kim, Josh, 2020 June 18; Series 2
    Alumni interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:27:33
  - Interview: Kusma, Tyler, 2020 June 22; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in Political Science interviewed by Sydney Teabout. Length of interview: 1:00:06
  - Interview: Lim, Katherine, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:50:39
  - Interview: LoyaconoBustos, Joseph, 2020 June 22; Series 2
    Alumni from American Studies interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:30:02
  - Interview: Magallanes, Evan, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in Political Science and Geography interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:53:07
  - Interview: Mason, Courtney, 2020 June 12; Series 2
    Graduate student in American Studies interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:39:38
  - Interview: Probolus, Kimberly [Restricted], 2020 July 14; Series 2
    Faculty member interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:39:58
    Conditions Governing Access
    This oral history is restricted for fifteen years, and will be opened July 14, 2035.
  - Interview: Ragland, Marisa, 2020 June 23; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in American Studies interviewed by Sydney Teabout. Length of interview: 0:47:51
  - Interview: Reyes, Madeline, 2020 June 24; Series 2
    Graduate student in the Milken School for Physical Therapy interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:28:02
  - Interview: Sullivan, Emma, 2020 June 23; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in Political Science/Criminal Justice interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:38:10
  - Interview: Teabout, Sydney, 2020 June 12; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:40:09
  - Interview: Wald, Gayle, 2020 July 1; Series 2
    Professor and department chair of American Studies interviewed by Sydney Teabout. Length of interview: 0:50:45
  - Interview: Whitcomb, Maya, 2020 July 8; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in International Affairs interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:38:23
  - Interview: Williams, Christian, 2020 June 23; Series 2
    Undergraduate student in International Affairs interviewed by Lexi Ross. Length of interview: 0:45:22
  - Interview: Zakes, Jeslyn, 2020 July 14; Series 2
    Alumni interviewed by Courtney Mason. Length of interview: 0:44:39
  - Interview: Bose, Sneeha, 2020 November 02; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Kim Probolus. Length of interview: 0:59:17
    Oral history is part of volume 2, the second grouping that was transferred to the University Archives.
  - Interview: Probolus, Kim [Restricted], 2020 November 02; Series 2
    Graduate student/part-time faculty interviewed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:53:50
    Embargoed until 4/15/2036.
  - Interview: McCulloch, Justin, 2020 November 03; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interveiwed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:35:16
  - Interview: Lange, Brandon, 2020 November 03; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:23:00
  - Interview: Kumar, Paaras, 2020 November 03; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:39:57
  - Interview: Epstein, Skylar, 2020 November 05; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:41:50
  - Interview: Venezky, Emily, 2020 November 06; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Sneeha Bose. Length of interview: 0:36:15
  - Interview: Hughes, Tim [Restricted], 2020 November 06; Series 2
    Alumni interviewed by Kim Probolus. Length of interview: 0:49:10
    Embargoed until 12/31/2025
  - Interview: Vargo, Kelley, 2020 December 24; Series 2
    GW staff member interviewed by Kim Probolus. Length of interview: 1:00:46
  - Interview: Griffin, Jeremiah, 2020 November 12; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Emily Gunnoy. Length of interview: 0:50:18
  - Interview: Meloling, Jack and Dasilva, Celsa, 2020 November 13; Series 2
    Undergraduate students that interviewed each other. Length of interview: 0:39:34
  - Interview: Ritthaworn, Richana, 2020 November 14; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Grace Mittenzwei. Length of interview: 0:54:24
  - Interview: Carr, Rebecca, 2020 November 14; Series 2
    Philosophy faculty member interviewed by Hector "Toji" Almanza. Length of interview: 0:25:37
  - Interview: Almanza, Hector, 2020 November 14; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Emily Scicli. Length of interview: 0:19:08
  - Interview: El-Gazairly, Noor, 2020 November 15; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Noah Chin. Length of interview: 0:42:11
  - Interview: Scicli, Emily, 2020 November 15; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Noah Zaidan. Length of interview: 0:29:51
  - Interview: Gunnoy, Emily S., 2020 November 24; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Jeremiah Griffin. Length of interview: 1:08:34
  - Interview: Chin, Noah, 2020 December 03; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Noor El-Gazairly. Length of interview: 0:52:03
  - Interview: Mittenzwei, Grace, 2020 December 29; Series 2
    Undergraduate student interviewed by Richana Ritthaworn. Length of interview: 1:02:34
  - Photographs, 2020-2021; Series 2
    Photographs captured by students when GW first went to virtual learning, after COVID-19.
  - Videos, 2020-2021; Series 2
    Videos captured by students after GW went to virtual learning after COVID-19.
  - Documents, 2020-2021; Series 2
- Records, 2020-2021; Series 3
  Beginning soon after the school went to online only and staff and faculty began working from home, the University Archivist began to collect the stories which document the GW community's experience during Covid-19.
  Custodial History
  These materials were all collected by the University Archivist.
  - Student survey, 2020; Series 3; 1 digital object(s) All responses to survey collected into single spreadsheet.